Register of the Norwood F. Allman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Norwood F. Allman papers
1929-1987
87042
Hoover Institution Archives
26 manuscript boxes, 4 envelopes (11.2 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, correspondence, radio broadcast transcripts, memoranda, reports, notes, biographical card files, and clippings relating to conditions in China (especially in Shanghai) before and after 1949, American-Chinese relations, and American intelligence activities in China during World War II. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Allman, Norwood F. (Norwood Francis), 1893-1987
Access
Collection is open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1987.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1893, July 24 Born, Union Hall, Virginia
1916 Law degree, University of Virginia
1916 Student interpreter at U.S. Legation, Peking, China
1916-1923 Served in Consulates in Antung, Tientsin, Tsinan, Tsingtao, Chungking, and Shanghai
1923-1941 Member, Shanghai Volunteer Corps
1924 Resigned from consular service
1924-1933 Honorary Consul for Mexico in Shanghai, China
1924-1950 Practiced law in Shanghai, China
1927-1935 Instructor at Comparative Law School of China, Soochow University, Shanghai, China
1937-1941 Editor and publisher, Shen Pao, Shanghai, China
1940-41 Member, Shanghai Municipal Council
1941-42 Interned at Stanley (Japanese) Prison Camp, Hongkong
1942-45 Chief, Far East Section, Secret Intelligence Branch, U.S. Office of Strategic Services
1943 Author, Shanghai Lawyer
1948-49 Editor and publisher, The China Press, Shanghai, China
1950, October Left Shanghai for the United States
1954-56 Associate Editor, Business International, New York City
1961-64 Far East Editor, Broadcast Editorial Reports, New York City
1987, April 30 Died, Carlisle, Pennsylvania
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
United States. Office of Strategic Services.; Americans--China.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; China--History--1949-1976.; China--History--Republic, 1912-1949.; China.; Journalists.; Secret service--United States.; Shanghai (China); United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Foreign relations--China.; United States--Foreign relations.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; World War, 1939-1945--Secret service.; World War, 1939-1945.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1940-1987
  Scope and Contents note
  This file contains records of N. Allman's career and family, including correspondence, certificates, and clippings.
  - Biographical File, 1940-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1929-1982
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Abbott Laboratories International Company, 1957 (Folder 4)
  - Acme Code Company, Inc., 1956-57 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allis Chalmers Manufacturing Company, 1956-57 (Folder 6)
  - Allman, N. F., 1948 (Folder 7)
  - American Association of Advertising Agencies, 1956 (Folder 8)
  - American Bank Note Company, 1956 (Folder 9)
  - American Cyanamid Company, 1957 (Folder 10)
  - American Express Company, 1956-57 (Folder 11)
  - American Foreign Insurance Association, 1956-57 (Folder 12)
  - American Independent Oil Company, 1956-57 (Folder 13)
  - American Indonesian Chamber of Commerce, 1956 (Folder 14)
  - American International Underwriters Corporation, 1956 (Folder 15)
  - American Machine and Foundry Company, 1958 (Folder 16)
  - American Trust Company, 1956 (Folder 17)
  - Amoss, Ulius, 1960 (Folder 18)
  - Amsinck Sonne and Company, 1956 (Folder 19)
  - An, A. Y., 1949 (Folder 20)
  - Argus Cameras, Inc., 1956 (Folder 21)
  - Armstrong, O. K., 1956 (Folder 22)
  - Atlantic, Gulf and Pacific Company, 1956 (Folder 23)
  - Au, David, 1957 (Folder 24)
  - Automatic Electric Company, 1956 (Folder 25)
  - Avco Manufacturing Corporation, 1956 (Folder 26)
  - Avegno, J. Bernard, 1956-57 (Folder 27)
  - Baldwin, Hanson W., 1950 (Folder 28)
  - Bank of America, 1956 (Folder 29)
  - Bankers Trust Company, 1956 (Folder 30)
  - Barrett, Edward W. and Associates, 1956 (Folder 31)
  - Bates, J. A., 1956 (Folder 32)
  - Beam Instrument Corporation, 1956 (Folder 33)
  - Birla, G. D., n.d. (Folder 34)
  - Birla, L. N., 1955 (Folder 35)
  - Black, Robert G., 1961 (Folder 36)
  - Bolander, Tage, 1956 (Folder 37)
  - Bond, W. C., 1954 (Folder 38)
  - Borden Company, 1956-1975 (Folder 39)
  - Boyd, Ralph, 1957 (Folder 40)
  - Bradford, Peter, 1956-1975 (Folder 41)
  - Bristol-Myers International Corporation, 1956 (Folder 42)
  - British Consulate General, Shanghai, 1950 (Folder 43)
  - Brown and Williamson Tobacco Corporation, 1956 (Folder 44)
  - Bryan, Edward Kedar, 1952-53 (Folder 45)
  - Bryan, Robert T., 1954 (Folder 46)
  - Bullis, Harry A., 1953-54 (Folder 47)
  - Bullock, Calvin, 1956 (Folder 48)
  - Byoir, Carl, 1956 (Folder 49)
  - California Texas Oil Company, Ltd., 1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Carborundum Company, 1956 (Folder 2)
  - Carroll, Charles T., 1959 (Folder 3)
  - Chang, K. S., 1956 (Folder 4)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1956 (Folder 5)
  - Chemical Corn Exchange Bank, 1956-57 (Folder 6)
  - Chen, Li-fu, 1955 (Folder 7)
  - Chen, S. T., 1960 (Folder 8)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's, Inc., 1956-57 (Folder 9)
  - Chiang, Kai-shek, 1955 (Folder 10)
  - Chicago Association of Commerce and Industry, 1956-57 (Folder 11)
  - Chicago Corporation, 1956 (Folder 12)
  - Chie, P. S., 1955 (Folder 13)
  - Chieh, Kan-ho, 1956 (Folder 14)
  - Choukanoff, Boyan, 1957 (Folder 15)
  - Christopher Trading Corporation, 1956 (Folder 16)
  - Clark Equipment International, 1956 (Folder 17)
  - Clayton Manufacturing Company, 1956 (Folder 18)
  - Cleary, Gottlieb, Friendly and Ball, 1956 (Folder 19)
  - Clement, Harry G., 1955 (Folder 20)
  - Coca-Cola Company, 1956-57 (Folder 21)
  - Colgate-Palmolive Company, 1956 (Folder 22)
  - Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government, 1954 (Folder 23)
  - Connell Brothers Company, Ltd., 1956 (Folder 24)
  - Consolidated Chemical Industries, 1956 (Folder 25)
  - Continental Diamond Fibre Company, 1956 (Folder 26)
  - Continental Foundry and Machine Company, 1956 (Folder 27)
  - Cook, Jackson, 1957 (Folder 28)
  - Cooper, John S., 1951 (Folder 29)
  - Corcoran, Youngman and Rowe, 1956 (Folder 30)
  - Corning Glass Works, 1956 (Folder 31)
  - Couch, William (Collier's Encyclopedia), 1952-53 (Folder 32)
  - Counterattack, 1956 (Folder 33)
  - Cox, Langford, Stoddard and Cutler, 1956 (Folder 34)
  - Crockett, Albert, 1957 (Folder 35)
  - Crown Zellerbach Corporation, 1957 (Folder 36)
  - Cuba, Secretary of State, 1929 (Folder 37)
  - Dean, Arthur H., 1954 (Folder 38)
  - Deepe, Beverly, 1960 (Folder 39)
  - Deputy, James J., 1954 (Folder 40)
  - Diniz, Adelino, 1951-57 (Folder 41)
  - Diniz, F. X., 1954 (Folder 42)
  - Ditto, Inc., 1956 (Folder 43)
  - Dodge and Seymour, Ltd., 1956 (Folder 44)
  - Dollar, R. Stanley, 1951 (Folder 45)
  - Donovan, William J., 1953-56 (Folder 46)
  - Du Berrier, Hilaire, 1957-1961 (Folder 47)
  - Duff, J. Arthur, 1957-59 (Folder 48)
  - Dulles, John Foster, 1957 (Folder 49)
  - Duval, Jo, 1955 (Folder 50)
  - Dzau, Linson, 1950-53 (Folder 51)
  - Eastbound Corporation, 1956 (Folder 52)
  - Eastman Kodak Company, 1956-57 (Folder 53)
  - Electrolux Corporation, 1956 (Folder 54)
  - Eli Lilly and Company, 1956-57 (Folder 55)
  - Elks, 1956-57 (Folder 56)
  - Espinosa y Prieto, Eduardo, 1941 (Folder 57)
  - Ethyl Corporation, 1956 (Folder 58)
  - Eversharp, Inc., 1956 (Folder 59)
  - Export-Import Bank of Washington, 1957 (Folder 60)
  - Export Managers Club of New York, 1956 (Folder 61)
  - Fairbanks, Morse and Company, 1956 (Folder 62)
  - Fairchild Publications, 1957 (Folder 63)
  - Fantus Factory Locating Company, 1956 (Folder 64)
  - Far East America Council of Commerce and Industry, 1956-57 (Folder 65)
  - Farrell, James, 1956 (Folder 66)
  - Federal Enterprises, Inc., 1956 (Folder 67)
  - Ferguson, H. K., Company, 1956 (Folder 68)
  - Fertilizer Corporation of America, 1956 (Folder 69)
  - Finkelstein, David, 1960 (Folder 70)
  - First National City Bank of New York, 1956-57 (Folder 71)
  - Firth Sterling, Inc., 1956 (Folder 72)
  - Fitz Gibbon, R. E., 1962 (Folder 73)
  - Flying Tiger Line, Inc., 1956 (Folder 74)
  - Forbes Magazine of Business, 1956 (Folder 75)
  - Ford, M. C., 1955 (Folder 76)
  - Ford Foundation, 1953 (Folder 77)
  - Foreign Traders Association of Philadelphia, 1956 (Folder 78)
  - Foye, Arthur B., 1951 (Folder 79)
  - Frawley Corporation, 1956 (Folder 80)
  - Frazar and Company, 1956 (Folder 81)
  - Fritz, Chester, 1958 (Folder 82)
  - Fry Corporation, 1956 (Folder 83)
  - Fu Chung International Corporation, 1956 (Folder 84)
  - Gallop Import and Export Company, Inc., 1951-55 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - General American Transportation Corporation, 1956 (Folder 2)
  - General Dynamics Corporation, 1956-57 (Folder 3)
  - General Electric Company, 1956-57 (Folder 4)
  - General Mills, Inc., 1956 (Folder 5)
  - General Motors Corporation, 1956-57 (Folder 6)
  - Getz Brothers Company, 1956 (Folder 7)
  - Gillette Company, 1956 (Folder 8)
  - Golding, William, 1964-65 (Folder 9)
  - Graham, John and Company, Inc., 1956 (Folder 10)
  - Grolier Society, Inc., 1956 (Folder 11)
  - Guerdon Corporation, 1956 (Folder 12)
  - Haglund, H. E., 1951 (Folder 13)
  - Hajek, Hans J., 1954-1961 (Folder 14)
  - Hamilton Wright Organization, Inc., 1957 (Folder 15)
  - Harnischfeger Corporation, 1956-57 (Folder 16)
  - Harper, Wallace, 1951-52 (Folder 17)
  - Hayden, Stone and Company, 1956 (Folder 18)
  - Healy, Baillie and Burke, 1963-64 (Folder 19)
  - Heinzerling, Herbert, 1954-58 (Folder 20)
  - Helseth, C. A. S., 1957 (Folder 21)
  - Hemisphere Commerce Associates, 1952 (Folder 22)
  - Hill and Knowlton, Inc., 1957 (Folder 23)
  - Hoffman, Paul A., 1952 (Folder 24)
  - Hsia, Ping-fang, 1961 (Folder 25)
  - Hsu, Leonard, 1957 (Folder 26)
  - Hu, William, 1953-54 (Folder 27)
  - Huizer, Pieter, 1956 (Folder 28)
  - Hunt, George P., 1956 (Folder 29)
  - Hunt, William P., 1955-56 (Folder 30)
  - Hunter, Edward, 1956 (Folder 31)
  - Indiana Construction Company, 1956 (Folder 32)
  - Ingalls Shipbuilding Corporation, 1956 (Folder 33)
  - Interchemical Corporation, 1956 (Folder 34)
  - Intercontinental Hotels Corporation, 1956 (Folder 34A)
  - Inter-Fiduciaries, Inc., 1955-57 (Folder 35)
  - International Basic Economy Corporation, 1956-57 (Folder 36)
  - IBM World Trade Corporation, 1957 (Folder 37)
  - International Cooperation Administration, 1956-57 (Folder 38)
  - International Harvester Export Company, 1956 (Folder 39)
  - International Interview, 1966 (Folder 41)
  - International Ore and Fertilizer Corporation, 1956 (Folder 42)
  - International Telephone and Telegraph Corporation, 1951, 1956 (Folder 43)
  - Ironmonger, Richard (Painter, Bill), 1959 (Folder 44)
  - Isthmian Lines, Inc., 1957 (Folder 45)
  - Jack, Charles, 1982 (Folder 46)
  - Jardine, Matheson and Company, 1949 (Folder 47)
  - Jensen-McLean Company, 1956 (Folder 48)
  - Jimenez, Enrique, 1933 (Folder 49)
  - Judd, Walter, 1952-53, 1957 (Folder 50)
  - Kansas City Chamber of Commerce, 1956-57 (Folder 51)
  - Kirby, Nancy, 1958 (Folder 52)
  - Kliene, Gavin, 1951 (Folder 53)
  - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1952-56 (Folder 54)
  - Kops, Charles, 1960 (Folder 55)
  - Kops, Paul F., 1981 (Folder 56)
  - Kung, Lee Wong, 1958 (Folder 57)
  - Lake Shore Engineering Company, 1956 (Folder 58)
  - Langdon, Kay, 1956 (Folder 59)
  - Lapham, Roger D., 1956 (Folder 60)
  - Lee, Harry, 1955 (Folder 61)
  - Li, K. C., 1957 (Folder 62)
  - Libby-Owens-Ford Glass Company, 1956-57 (Folder 63)
  - Lin, D. Y., 1950-1967 (Folder 64)
  - Little, Arthur D., Inc., 1956 (Folder 65)
  - Liu, Frank (Exner, Frank), 1950-52 (Folder 66)
  - Lone Star Cement Corporation, 1956 (Folder 67)
  - Lutey, Kent, 1954-57 (Folder 68)
  - Ma, William C. S., 1964 (Folder 69)
  - McGovern, W. M., 1948 (Folder 70)
  - McGraw and Company, 1956-57 (Folder 71)
  - Madison International, 1956 (Folder 72)
  - Manufacturers Representative, 1956 (Folder 73)
  - Manufacturers Trust Company, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Marquis, A. N., Company, 1952 (Folder 2)
  - May, A. Wilfred, 1957 (Folder 3)
  - Merck-Sharp and Dohme International, 1956-57 (Folder 4)
  - Merrow, Chester E., 1953 (Folder 5)
  - Metals and Control Corporation, 1956 (Folder 6)
  - Mighty Mover Company, 1956-57 (Folder 7)
  - Miller, Allen, 1956 (Folder 8)
  - Milmine Bodman and Company, 1956 (Folder 9)
  - Mizelle, William R., 1954 (Folder 10)
  - Moffitt, James K., 1957 (Folder 11)
  - Mokrejs, John, 1956-57 (Folder 12)
  - Mollinkrodt Chemical Works, 1956 (Folder 13)
  - Momsen, Richard P., 1956 (Folder 14)
  - Monarch Marking System Company, 1956 (Folder 15)
  - Monsanto Chemical Company, 1956 (Folder 16)
  - Morgan Stanley and Company, 1956 (Folder 17)
  - Morris and Van Wormer, 1956-57 (Folder 18)
  - Moy, Ernest K., 1951-53 (Folder 19)
  - Mullen, Clifton R., 1958 (Folder 20)
  - Muller and Phipps Asia Limited, 1956 (Folder 21)
  - Murray, Edwards, 1957 (Folder 22)
  - Murray Company of Texas, Inc., 1956 (Folder 23)
  - Myers, H. C., 1940 (Folder 24)
  - Mytinger and Casselberry, Inc., 1956 (Folder 25)
  - Nanyang Cotton Mills, 1956 (Folder 26)
  - National Carbon Company, 1956 (Folder 27)
  - National City Bank of New York, 1956 (Folder 28)
  - National Foreign Trade Council, 1957 (Folder 29)
  - National Planning Association, 1957 (Folder 30)
  - Neblett, Adelaide, 1955 (Folder 31)
  - New York City Colony, 1951 (Folder 32)
  - New York Life Insurance Company, 1956 (Folder 33)
  - Nutrilite Products, Inc., 1956 (Folder 34)
  - Ort, Karl, 1951 (Folder 35)
  - Overseas Economic Operations Task Force, 1954 (Folder 36)
  - Parke, Davis and Company, 1956 (Folder 37)
  - Parker Pen Company, 1956 (Folder 38)
  - Parsons, Walter S., 1951 (Folder 39)
  - Patterson, A. L., 1957 (Folder 40)
  - Pattison, A. P., 1956 (Folder 41)
  - Pennault International Corporation, 1956 (Folder 42)
  - Pepsi-Cola Company, 1956 (Folder 43)
  - Pfizar International Subsidiaries, 1956 (Folder 44)
  - Philco International Corporation, 1956 (Folder 45)
  - Philippe Brothers, Inc., 1956 (Folder 46)
  - Philippine American Chamber of Commerce, Inc., 1956 (Folder 47)
  - Pi Chiao Law Society, 1962 (Folder 48)
  - Potter, John S., 1960 (Folder 49)
  - Pownall, William R., 1956 (Folder 50)
  - Price, A., n.d. (Folder 51)
  - Rand Corporation, 1957 (Folder 52)
  - Ray-O-Vac, 1957 (Folder 53)
  - Read, Vaughan, 1953-54 (Folder 54)
  - Readers Digest, 1956 (Folder 55)
  - Rediker, Norris, 1956 (Folder 56)
  - Remington Rand, Inc., 1957 (Folder 57)
  - Republic Steel Corporation, 1956 (Folder 58)
  - Reynolds Metals Company, 1956-57 (Folder 59)
  - Rheem Manufacturing Company, 1956 (Folder 60)
  - Richardson Foundation, Inc., 1956 (Folder 61)
  - Ride, L. T., 1948 (Folder 62)
  - Rochester Ropes, Inc., 1956 (Folder 63)
  - Rockefeller, David, 1951 (Folder 64)
  - Rocky Mount, Franklin County, Virginia, 1958-1960 (Folder 65)
  - Rogers Corporation, 1957 (Folder 66)
  - Ross, Julia, 1953 (Folder 67)
  - Royal McBee Corporation, 1957 (Folder 68)
  - Saco-Lowell Shops, 1956 (Folder 69)
  - Safety Car Heating and Lighting Company, 1956 (Folder 70)
  - San Francisco Chamber of Commerce, 1956-57 (Folder 71)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1956 (Folder 72)
  - Schapira, Arthur, 1956-1962 (Folder 73)
  - Schroeder Banking Corporation, 1957 (Folder 74)
  - Seamless Rubber Company, 1957 (Folder 75)
  - Seattle First National Bank, 1956 (Folder 76)
  - Servel Inc., 1956 (Folder 77)
  - Seymour, L. D. and Company, 1956 (Folder 78)
  - Shanghai American School, 1950 (Folder 79)
  - Shao, Albert T., 1956 (Folder 80)
  - Shaw, Bruno, 1956 (Folder 81)
  - Shearman and Sterling and Wright, 1956 (Folder 82)
  - Shen, Thomas C., 1957 (Folder 83)
  - Sheng, Chenhua, 1952 (Folder 84)
  - Sheridan, Frank J., 1950-51 (Folder 85)
  - Shields, Leighton, 1947 (Folder 86)
  - Shriro Trading Corporation, 1951-53 (Folder 87)
  - Sie, C. K., 1953-54 (Folder 88)
  - Simoniz Company, 1956 (Folder 89)
  - Simonsen, Fred, 1954-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - SKIL Corporation, 1956 (Folder 2)
  - Slaton, Clyde, 1951 (Folder 3)
  - Smith, A. O., Corporation, 1957 (Folder 4)
  - Smith, Howard Worth, 1951 (Folder 5)
  - Smith, Tom, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Smyth, William H., 1955 (Folder 7)
  - Sokolsky, George, 1952-54 (Folder 8)
  - Sourwine, J. G., 1956 (Folder 9)
  - Southern Company, 1956 (Folder 10)
  - Southsea Cotton Mills, 1956 (Folder 11)
  - Southwestern Engineering Company, 1957 (Folder 12)
  - Sprague, C. H., 1958 (Folder 13)
  - Springborg, A., 1958 (Folder 14)
  - Standard Vacuum Company, 1957 (Folder 15)
  - Starr, C. V. and Company, 1956 (Folder 16)
  - State Historical Society of Wisconsin, 1966 (Folder 17)
  - Stearns, Jessie, 1951 (Folder 18)
  - Stephens, Donald, 1957 (Folder 19)
  - Stephenson Corporation, 1956 (Folder 20)
  - Stone, C. Y., 1953-54 (Folder 21)
  - Stumvoll, Felix, 1951 (Folder 22)
  - Sun, Edwin, 1955 (Folder 23)
  - Sun Oil Company, 1956 (Folder 24)
  - Sung, L. P., 1950-1966 (Folder 25)
  - Swezey, H. Joseph, 1957 (Folder 26)
  - Sylvania Electric Products, Inc., 1956 (Folder 27)
  - System Auto Parts and Garages, Inc., 1956 (Folder 28)
  - Tan, W. H., 1960 (Folder 29)
  - Tang, Kong, 1960 (Folder 30)
  - Technical Missions, Inc., 1956 (Folder 31)
  - Thompson, Harold J., 1953 (Folder 32)
  - Ting, Wen-yuan, 1953 (Folder 33)
  - Tong, Hollington K., 1956 (Folder 34)
  - Tradewell Company, 1951 (Folder 35)
  - Transamerica Corporation, 1956 (Folder 36)
  - Tsao, L. E., 1955 (Folder 37)
  - Tung, Ernest, 1953-1971 (Folder 38)
  - Underwood Corporation, 1956 (Folder 39)
  - Union Bag and Paper Company, 1956 (Folder 40)
  - United Commercial Bank, 1956 (Folder 41)
  - U.S. Chamber of Commerce, 1956 (Folder 42)
  - U.S. Department of State, Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce, 1943, 1957 (Folder 43)
  - U.S. Department of State, 1951-52 (Folder 44)
  - United States Steel Corporation, 1956 (Folder 45)
  - United States Steel Export Company, 1956-57 (Folder 46)
  - Universal Leaf Tobacco Company, 1956 (Folder 47)
  - Upjohn Company, 1956 (Folder 48)
  - Van Reekum Paper Company, 1951 (Folder 49)
  - Vaswani, Gobind N., 1960 (Folder 50)
  - Vilas, George, 1956 (Folder 51)
  - Villamin, Vincente, 1956 (Folder 52)
  - Vogeler, Robert A., 1952 (Folder 53)
  - Wah Chang Corporation, 1956 (Folder 54)
  - Warner-Lambert International, 1957 (Folder 55)
  - Wedemeyer, Albert C., 1951 (Folder 56)
  - Weirton Steel Company, 1956 (Folder 57)
  - Westinghouse Company, 1956-57 (Folder 58)
  - Westrex Corporation, 1956-57 (Folder 59)
  - White, J. G., Engineering Corporation, 1956-57 (Folder 60)
  - White, Weld and Company, 1956 (Folder 61)
  - Wilbur-Ellis Company, 1956-57 (Folder 62)
  - Wilhelm, John, 1957 (Folder 63)
  - Williams, J. C., 1966 (Folder 64)
  - Willoughby, Charles A., 1952 (Folder 65)
  - Wilson, John, 1953 (Folder 66)
  - Wilson, Richard (The Far Easterner), 1954-57 (Folder 67)
  - Wilson, T. B., 1957 (Folder 68)
  - Wong, James Y., 1955 (Folder 69)
  - Wyoming, University of, 1971 (Folder 70)
  - Yang, Yin, 1958, 1963 (Folder 71)
  - Yao, Arthur, 1952 (Folder 72)
  - Yi Ming Navigation Corporation, 1961-63 (Folder 73)
  - York Corporation, 1956 (Folder 74)
  - Yui, O. K., 1954 (Folder 75)
  - Yun, Tien Chiang, 1962 (Folder 76)
  - Zellerbach Paper Company, 1956 (Folder 77)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Folder 78)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1943-1966
  Typewritten and printed copies of speeches and writings of N. Allman with related correspondence and notes, arranged chronologically.
  - Shanghai Lawyer, 1943. Correspondence, notes, flyers and other material pertaining to the book Shanghai Lawyer. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Testimony of Mr. N. F. Allman, House Foreign Affairs Committee, Mimeograph., March 1, 1948. (Folder 2)
  - "Let's Talk Sense (A Speech for Eisenhower Supporters)," Typescript (carbon copy)., 1952. (Folder 3)
  - "China: Eyewitness " 1953. Printed copy. Correspondence included., 1916-1950 (Folder 4)
  - "Dr. Linus Carl Pauling - Off-side in Cold War?", Typescript (carbon copy)., August 29, 1960. (Folder 5)
  - "Sino-Soviet Relations," Typescript (carbon copy)., September 27, 1960. (Folder 6)
  - "Myth of Sino-Soviet Split," Typescript (carbon copy)., December 30, 1960. (Folder 7)
  - "Southeast Asian Volcano," Typescript (carbon copy)., January 6, 1961. (Folder 8)
  - "Laos Looms Large," Typescript., March 17, 1961. (Folder 9)
  - "Peking and Latin America," Typescript (carbon copy)., March 24, 1961. (Folder 10)
  - "Peking Invades the Americas," Typescript., March 28, 1961. (Folder 11)
  - "John Birch Society," Typescript (carbon copy)., April 18, 1961. (Folder 12)
  - Broadcast Editorial Reports - "Opioncasts," New York City, Mimeograph., 1961-62. (Folder 13-14)
  - "Belligerent Peking War Lords," Typescript (photocopy)., 1966. (Folder 15)
  - "Delivery of China to Communism - Eye Witness, " n.d. Typescript (carbon copy)., 1916-1950 (Folder 16)
  - "History - Far East, SI," Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 17)
  - "A Suggested Silver Plan for China," Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 18)
  - "Transliteration of 'Coca-Cola' Trade-Mark to Chinese Characters," Printed copy., n.d. (Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, notes, drafts, and other material relating to speeches and writings, 1951-53 (Folder 20-21)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1943-1987
  Correspondence, reports, memoranda, printed matter, clippings, biographical cards, and other materials arranged alphabetically by subject or by last name of individual.
  - Abe, Nobuyuki (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Abegg, Lilly (Folder 2)
  - Acquino, Benigno (Folder 3)
  - Aguinaldo, Emilio (Folder 4)
  - Ah, Prince (Folder 5)
  - Ahlwein, W. (Folder 6)
  - Ai, Henry (Folder 7)
  - Ai Sha (Folder 8)
  - Aikawa, Yoshisuke (Folder 9)
  - Akchura, Usuf Bey (Folder 10)
  - Aksalur, Izzetin (Folder 10A)
  - Albeniz, Filipe (Folder 11)
  - Alcott, Carroll (Folder 12)
  - Allen, Devere (Folder 14)
  - Allen, Donald M. (Folder 15)
  - Alley, Norman William (Folder 16)
  - Allman, Thomas Lee (Folder 17)
  - Alsop, Joseph (Folder 18)
  - Amau, Eiji (Folder 19)
  - American Engineering Corporation (Folder 20)
  - American Food Agencies, Fed. Inc., U.S.A. (Folder 21)
  - American Industrial Products Company (Folder 22)
  - Anami, General (Folder 23)
  - Anderson, Paul M. (Folder 24)
  - Ando, Rikichi (Folder 25)
  - Antionoff, N. (Folder 26)
  - Ao, Ta-ching (Folder 27)
  - Aoki, Kazuo (Folder 28)
  - Aoki, Minoru (Folder 29)
  - Appleman, Morris (Folder 30)
  - Ardoni, Dr. (Folder 31)
  - Armstrong, O. K. (Folder 32)
  - Arnholdt, Charles H. (Folder 33)
  - Arshad, Ali (Folder 34)
  - Ashida, Hitoshi (Folder 35)
  - Atal, M. (Folder 36)
  - Au, David (Folder 37)
  - Aung San, Major General (Folder 38)
  - Aw, Boon Haw (Folder 39)
  - Ba Maung (Folder 40)
  - Ba Maw, Dr. (Folder 41)
  - Bachman, George (Folder 42)
  - Bachy, Lt. Comdr. (Folder 43)
  - Baker, John Earl (Folder 44)